Colleen O'Brien

© colleen-o-brien.com | ♥ colleenobrien3 | in colleen-o-brien3

With a background in writing and rhetoric, I bring leadership via strong communication skills to my software engineering team. I take a creative holistic approach to development, keeping the overall goal of exceptional user experience at the forefront of each project.

DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Immersive Student General Assembly | Washington, D.C.

Jan 2020 - Present

Full-time, 3 months, 500+ hours of in-depth hands-on training in trending full-stack software engineering technologies and methodologies

PROJECTS

CoTripper — Team Client Project

- Led backend team in planning and setting up database and api
- Created ERD with LucidChart
- Backend: Python, Django REST Framework, PostgreSQL
- Frontend: React.js
- cotripper.co
- github.com/CotripperPlatform/CoTrip

Recipe Rolodex — Team MERN App

- Created an app for posting and viewing recipes.
- Backend: MongoDB, Express, Node.js recipe-roledex.herokuapp.com
- Frontend: React.js recipe-rolodex.netlify.com

Villanova Basketball Trivia — Solo Frontend Game

- Created user interface for trivia, implemented logic for progressing through game and calculating score.
- Vanilla JavaScript villanova-bball-trivia.netlify.com

War Card Game — Solo Frontend Game

- Developed functional logic for simulating the card game war in the browser console.
- Vanilla JavaScript colleenobrien3.github.io/game-of-war/

EXPERIENCE

Beach Lifeguard | Dewey Beach, DE AUG 2015 - MAY 2019

- -Completed rigorous paramilitary style physical training
- -Prepared to perform open water rescue and first aid
- -Educated community on beach safety practices

Intramural Sports Referee | Villanova, PA JAN 2017 - MAY 2018

- -Refereed sports games to maximize safety and fairness
- -Kept track of fouls, scores, and statistics

Physical Therapy Intern | Sydney, Australia OCT 2017 - DEC 2017

- -Administered modalities such as ultrasound and spinal traction
- -Performed therapeutic massage and minor joint adjustments

Host/Busser | Wayne, PA JUN 2019 - AUG 2019

- -Coordinated reservations and seating placements
- -Expedited food delivery, ensuring order was met completely and on time

Nanny | Media, PA and Dover, DE AUG 2011 - SEPT 2018 (intermittently)

-Cared for up to three children at a time, all ages

407 P St. NW Washington, D.C. 20001 (302) 387-3405 colleen3117@gmail.com

DEVELOPMENT SKILLS

JavaScript

React.js

Node.js

Express

Python

Web Scraping

Django

Django REST Framework

PostgreSQL

Flask

Peewee

API Integration & Development

JSON Web Tokens

Application deployment

MongoDB

Mongoose

HTML

CSS

Storybook

Git

GitHub

Command Line

EDUCATION

Villanova University Honors

2015-2019 Cum Laude

Degree: BA Humanities Minors: Peace and Justice,

History, Honors

Presidential Scholars Program

Polytech High School

2011-2015

Valedictorian (class of 300) National Merit Scholar Master of Tech. in Physical Therapy Aide Track